Noah McDougall

1439 Buckhead Trail, Mt. Juliet, TN 37122

Cell: (865) 323-3873 | Email: noah.mcdougall@gmail.com Website: noahmcdougall.com

SUMMARY

Applied geoscientist with experience in oil and gas, mining, and geographic information systems. Adept at focusing technical and planning skills to achieve business results. Specializes in seismic interpretation, spatial analysis, coordinating projects, and automating tasks using advanced Excel knowledge and basic scripting in Python.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Nyrstar Tennessee Mines, Gordonsville, TX – Exploration Geologist

2017-17

Geoscientist guiding exploration operations for Gordonsville, Elmwood, and Cumberland mines.

- Monitored and ensured safe real-time operations for six drilling rigs.
- Planned both surface and underground drill targets for mineral exploration.
- Logged core, graded ore for assay, and populated geologic model.
- Maintained working relations with land owners and minimized ecological impact.

LandWorks, Houston, TX – Geographic Information Systems (GIS) Team Lead 2016–17 GIS mapping team lead supporting land management needs for various energy industry clients.

- Supervised a team tasked with mapping utility easements from legal documents.
- Developed ArcGIS addins using Python that save an estimated \$75K per life of project.
- Assisted alternative energy client with building an ArcGIS Online project and web portal.

BP, Houston, TX – Integrated Geophysicist

2013-16

Geoscientist in charge of reserve estimates, seismic reprocessing, model building, well planning and monitoring, and activity planning across three major Gulf of Mexico fields.

- Coordinated technical planning of a 4D seismic acquisition program.
- Worked with reservoir engineers to optimize the water injection program and future production.
- Built structurally complex, static reservoir Petrel model and model-building workflows.
- Reinterpreted reserve estimates for government compliance and Resource Support Package that led to major well design and activity plan updates.
- Designed the standard for Integrated Subsurface Description documentation and leveraged ArcGIS skills to standardize maps across reservoirs.

EDUCATION

BP Challenger T	raining Program – Integrated Geophysicist	2013–16
M.S. Geophysics	s, University of Arizona	2011–13
	GPA: 3.81/4.0	
B.S. Geology,	University of Tennessee, Knoxville	2007–11
	GPA: 3.89/4.0, Summa Cum Laude	
RESEARCH I	PROJECTS	
	f offshore Guinea post-rifting structures – plateau extension canism" - Graduate project (GSA 2013)	2011–13
ground penetro	rived correlation between ground conductivity and 100 MHz atting radar depth attenuation" - Undergraduate project, presented ssional conference (SAGEEP 2011)	2011
	ohysical investigation of karst features on intramural fields of of Tennessee, Knoxville" - Undergraduate project	2010
HONORS and	I AWARDS	
Edith L. Moore Nature Sanctuary Volunteer ArcGIS Manager, Houston		2015–17
Secretary of the Greater Houston Grotto		
Vice President of the UAGS (SEG sponsored club)		
Outstanding Graduate in Commencement Program		
Chancellor's Honors Extraordinary Professional Promise Award		2011
Undergraduate	GeoClub President	2010–11
SOFTWARE	EXPERIENCE	
Experience usin	g many forms of industry related software including:	

Experience using many forms of industry related software including:

• Landmark Software

 Landmark Software 	 MineSight 3D 	
• Petrel	• Surfer	
• IHS Kingdom	 AcQuire GIM Suite 	
• ESRI ArcGIS	• DGI CoViz	
• Roxar RMS	• QGIS	

Proficient in other drafting software such as Adobe Illustrator and Adobe Photoshop. Self-taught in Python, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, jQuery, Jade, Node JS, Gulp, and Git.